Let's start from the beginning.
Web coding is basically a way of building
software where you don't write every single line
of code yourself.
Instead, you just describe what you want in
plain English and the AI writes the code
for you.
You're still in control, you're guiding it, but
the actual typing and syntax is handled by
the AI.
The term was coined in early 2025 by
Andrej Karapathy, who used to lead AI at
Tesla and is also one of the founding
members of OpenAI.
He described his workflow pretty casually, something like,
I just see things, say things, run things,
and it mostly works.
That line stuck, and within weeks, everyone in
the development world was talking about web coding.
And by 2026, it stopped being just talk,
it became real.
Most developers now use AI coding tools daily.
Colin's dictionary even named it word of the
year.
Harvard is teaching it, and there's a dedicated
workshop called WebEx 2026 at major software engineering
conferences.
This isn't just hype anymore, it's a real
shift in how software is being built.
But here is the thing, web coding isn't
magic, and it doesn't replace thinking.
You're not just pressing a button and letting
AI build your startup while you sleep.
What's really changing is how you work.
Instead of writing code line by line, you're
telling the system what you want, you're giving
direction, and what you get out depends a
lot on how clearly you explain what you
need.